<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>github.com/atuttle/blog</title>
   
   <link>http://adamtuttle.codes</link>
   <description>It's one thing to write code. It's another to humanize technology so it serves a purpose in people's lives. &mdash; Luke Wroblewski</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Adam Tuttle</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>I Think Donald Trump Is an Idiot, but That Doesn't Mean I Think You Are</title>
	  <link>//trump-is-an-idiot-but-you-arent/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-07-07T08:15:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//trump-is-an-idiot-but-you-arent/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>There are a few moments in my life where I feel like I have truly grown as a person. Usually when I learn something profound and it sinks in immediately, and it&#39;s like a lightbulb has lit up over my head. I can think of at least two such moments that happened when I re-watched The West Wing early this year.</p>

<p>The first of which, and the one I want to talk about today, happened as I watched Episode 7 of Season 2, &quot;The Portland Trip.&quot; I&#39;ve embedded a random copy of it that I found online below. You <em>could</em> watch the entire episode, but if you want to jump straight to the part that I&#39;m thinking of, it starts at about the 27 minute mark.</p>

<p>(The West Wing is available on Netflix and I can&#39;t recommend it enough, regardless of your personal politics. You can also <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cI9HhNjXLu4">rent it on YouTube</a>.)</p>

<p><object width="576" height="432"><param name="movie" value="http://www.flasharc.com/bpr.swf"></param><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.flasharc.com/bpr.swf" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="576" height="432"></embed></object></p>

<p>And here&#39;s a transcript from <a href="http://www.westwingtranscripts.com/search.php?flag=getTranscript&amp;id=29">WestWingTranscripts.com</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p><strong>SKINNER:</strong>
Ask me the question.</p>

<p><strong>JOSH:</strong>
He compared homosexuality to kleptomania and sex addition, Matt.</p>

<p><strong>SKINNER:</strong>
Yes.</p>

<p><strong>JOSH:</strong>
The Majority Leader. The leader of your own party.</p>

<p><strong>SKINNER:</strong>
He was wrong and I told him so.</p>

<p><strong>JOSH:</strong>
For cryin&#39; out loud!</p>

<p><strong>SKINNER:</strong>
Ask me the question, Josh!</p>

<p><strong>JOSH:</strong>
How can you be a member of this party?!?</p>

<p><strong>SKINNER:</strong>
You&#39;ve been holding that in for way too long, man.</p>

<p><strong>JOSH:</strong>
This party who says that who you are is against the law.</p>

<p><strong>SKINNER:</strong>
You know, I never understand why you gun control people don&#39;t all join the
N.R.A. They&#39;ve
got two million members. You bring three million to the next meeting... call
a vote...
All those in favor of tossing guns - [Snaps fingers] - Bam! Move on.</p>

<p><strong>JOSH:</strong>
That&#39;s a heck of a strategy, Matt. I&#39;ll bring that up in a meeting.</p>

<p>Josh sighs heavily as he collapses into his chair.</p>

<p><strong>SKINNER:</strong>
I agree with 95% of the Republican platform. I believe in local government. I&#39;m
in favor
of individual rights rather than group rights. I believe free markets lead
to free people
and that the country needs a strong national defense. My life doesn&#39;t have
to be about
being a homosexual. It doesn&#39;t have to be entirely about that.</p>

<p>Josh looks at Skinner thoughtfully before deciding not to continue.</p>

<p><strong>JOSH:</strong>
Thanks for coming by.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>With the benefit of hindsight I can say that on many occasions in my life I&#39;ve thought about specific people as the embodiment of their position on a divisive issue: abortion, gun control, religious freedom, and yes, sexual equality.</p>

<p>When you are hyper focused on a single issue, especially when thinking about someone else, it becomes easy to forget about everything other than that issue; just as Josh Lyman did in the scene transcribed above. But we are all people. Human beings. With an infinite number of thoughts and emotions and desires and needs all struggling to find a place in our priorities. None of us does a perfect job of balancing those out; we all just do the best that we can with the information we&#39;ve got at the time.</p>

<p>I look at Donald Trump and see a privileged, racist, xenophobic, small-minded, and short-sighted individual whom I am terrified still has a chance of holding our Executive Office. At face value it can be mind blowing.</p>

<p>But you (and I mean that to be directed at his supporters) are just people. You have your own priorities based on your own wants and needs and emotions. I mean, maybe you&#39;re an open white supremacist and you like him because he shares your views on immigration. Or maybe you truly believe that Hillary Clinton is going to do something that you view as evil and voting Trump is your way of fighting back. It&#39;s also possible that you strongly believe in small government and free markets but you&#39;re tired of career politicians who turn their back on you the minute they&#39;re sworn into office. These are all legitimate reasons to support Trump, and it is your right to do so.</p>

<p>It would be easy to alias &quot;Trump Supporter&quot; to &quot;Racist Xenophobic Idiot&quot; in my brain, and I admit I have once or twice had those thoughts when seeing some of the coverage of his campaign and supporters. But that is not being honest to what I know to be true.</p>

<p>We&#39;re all just people, and we aren&#39;t defined by who we support in an election.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>TIL: Adding an SSL Cert to the JVM Inside a Docker Image</title>
	  <link>//TIL-adding-a-jvm-ssl-cert-docker/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-06-27T09:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//TIL-adding-a-jvm-ssl-cert-docker/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I&#39;ve been playing with Docker lately for a bunch of reasons, but topping that list is that it&#39;s everything I ever wanted out of Vagrant, and then some. (And what better thing to do on a camping trip after the kids are tucked into bed?) In some ways, the Dockerfile syntax is what I wish the Vagrantfile syntax was (shell script instead of Ruby). Anyway, here&#39;s a solution to an interesting problem I ran into today.</p>

<p>I need to make HTTP requests to the <a href="https://mailgun.com/app/dashboard">mailgun</a> API and their certificate isn&#39;t valid given the JVM cert store that I&#39;m inheriting in my Docker image. Of course, I just need to <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/36427118/751">download and import the certificate</a><sup>[1]</sup>, but it took me a little while to wrap my mind around the idiomatic Docker way of doing this.</p>

<p>After some hints from <a href="http://ryanguill.com/">Ryan</a> (to whom I owe cases and cases of beer for similarly helpful advice), and a little more googling and trial and error, this is what I came up with. In my Dockerfile, I&#39;ve added:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-Dockerfile" data-lang="Dockerfile">COPY ./res/mailgun.net.crt /opt/lucee/
<span class="k">ENV</span> LUCEE_CACERTS /opt/lucee/server/lucee-server/context/security/cacerts
<span class="k">RUN</span> keytool -noprompt -storepass password_here -import -alias mailgun -keystore <span class="k">${</span><span class="nv">LUCEE_CACERTS</span><span class="k">}</span> -file /opt/lucee/mailgun.net.crt
</code></pre></div>
<p>After copying my downloaded mailgun certificate file into the Docker image, I use the <code>keytool</code> command with options <code>-noprompt -storepass</code> to import it without prompting me for the store password.</p>

<p>As a refresher, to find all <code>cacerts</code> files on your (linux) machine, try this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-text" data-lang="text">find / -iname &#39;cacerts&#39;
</code></pre></div>
<p>This will list all files named cacerts on the system. In my Docker image, there were 4. I picked the one associated with <a href="http://lucee.org/">Lucee</a> because that&#39;s the app server I&#39;m working with in this case, but it&#39;s possible that importing to the JVM&#39;s store could have worked too. I just got lucky on my first guess, so I stopped there.</p>

<hr>

<p><small>1: On OSX I was able to download the certificate with Firefox following <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/36427118/751">these instructions</a>, and while I did select the &quot;der&quot; export type, it saved as a .crt file. Java did not complain about importing this file.</small></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Cobbler's Children Syndrome</title>
	  <link>//cobblers-children-syndrome/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-05-05T12:30:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//cobblers-children-syndrome/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>My old blog at <a href="http://fusiongrokker.com">fusiongrokker.com</a> was recently offline for more than 230 consecutive hours. Partly, the hosting company is to blame for this. I pay them for a service: A server, connected to the internet, with electricity; and this service was not being properly provided. But partly it is my own fault too.</p>

<p>230 hours is nine and a half days. At what point should I have decided to give up on them coming back online (after my numerous support tickets and phone calls went unanswered) and restored my website onto a new web host from my most recent backups? Well, before you can answer that question it&#39;s important to note that I didn&#39;t have backups. At least nothing recent.</p>

<p>Oops.</p>

<p>Fortunately, the server is back online now. Yes, I immediately made a backup of both the database and the files for the website. Fortunately, it&#39;s not changing in any meaningful way. Maybe a stray comment or two on old articles. Nothing I&#39;ll be overly worried about losing. And I intend to get it all converted over to this new blog eventually, with proper redirection from the old URLs. Eventually.</p>

<p>Eventually. That&#39;s the word that got me into trouble in the first place. Cobbler&#39;s Children Syndrome.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>The cobbler&#39;s children have no shoes</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is a <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/TheCobblersChildrenHaveNoShoes">common trope</a> that most people have probably heard of. On the off chance that you&#39;re one of today&#39;s <a href="https://xkcd.com/1053/">lucky 10,000</a>, it goes something like this: The cobbler, who makes shoes for a living &mdash;for some combination of reasons&mdash; doesn&#39;t provide shoes for her own children.</p>

<p>And it&#39;s not that big of a deal, most of the time. You can walk around most areas barefoot without too much trouble, aside from stores that won&#39;t let you in without shoes. But the problem with this mentality is that it fails you when you&#39;re desperate. When you find yourself facing a road litered with shards of glass and no choice but to cross it. You&#39;ll be cursing your former self for not investing in some shoes.</p>

<p>So it was with my blog&#39;s backups. Of course I had backups of <em>important</em> stuff. Things that <em>make me money</em>, like <a href="http://www.restassuredbook.com">my book</a> and websites I&#39;ve made for freelance clients. At face value, my personal blog didn&#39;t sound so important. <em>I&#39;ll get to it eventually</em>, I&#39;d think to myself.</p>

<p>Eight years later... that didn&#39;t work out so well for me.</p>

<p>I have no idea how much google-juice those old blog entries lost in the 9.5+ days they were offline, but it was definitely non-zero. I had friends tell me that they couldn&#39;t even find my blog in google search results if they were specifically searching for it. Crap.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2016/just_do_it.gif" alt="just do it"></p>

<p>So now it&#39;s a priority. Which is to say that it&#39;s been prioritized, somewhere near, but not at the top of, my list. I do have to keep doing things that pay the bills first. But after those, this is uh, one of, my top priorities.</p>

<p>There are a lot of things that we as software developers are prone to let slide like this. Version controlling tiny little side projects is another example. And there&#39;s only one appropriate response when addressing these questions in your head. There&#39;s really no other answer you can give.</p>

<p>Just do it.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>"Fork Me on GitHub" Stickers</title>
	  <link>//fork-me-stickers/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-04-20T10:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fork-me-stickers/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I have been going a little sticker-crazy lately, and I decided I wanted a &quot;Fork Me&quot; sticker, ala GitHub&#39;s <a href="https://github.com/blog/273-github-ribbons">Fork Me ribbons</a> (pro-tip: use <a href="https://github.com/aral/fork-me-on-github-retina-ribbons">these retina-friendly ones instead</a>) that are common for OSS developers to put onto their websites or their project websites. I couldn&#39;t find one anywhere, so I made one, and now you too can emblazon your favorite things with a &quot;Fork Me&quot; ribbon sticker.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.stickermule.com/marketplace/11734-fork-me"><img src="/assets/images/posts/2016/fork-me-screen-shot.png" alt="Fork Me ribbon sticker now available on StickerMule!"></a></p>

<p align="center"><a href="https://www.stickermule.com/marketplace/11734-fork-me">Click here to get yours!</a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Right Tool for the Job: Success Notifications</title>
	  <link>//the-right-tool-success-notifications/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-03-14T05:30:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-right-tool-success-notifications/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>In what I hope is the first in a long series of short posts describing small steps I&#39;m taking to <em>do the right thing&trade;</em>, today I want to talk about eliminating <em>yet another email notification</em>. In a way I guess you could say I&#39;m on a campaign against email, at least as a method of anything other than async remote communication.</p>

<p>Back in the dark ages of 2013 I gave a conference presentation on an open source tool that I use called <a href="http://www.bugloghq.com/">BugLogHQ</a>, an alternative to sending yourself emails containing debug information when an exception occurs in your app &ndash; and I hasten to reiterate: one with many advantages. My team and I still use BLHQ to this day, and it is remarkably better than emailing error debug information. <a href="/errors-are-best-when-emailed-said-nobody-ever/">You can see the conference session abstract and the slides here</a>. Not as good as being there, but it should give you an idea of how great BLHQ can be, comparatively.</p>

<p>Having solved the error logging problem, the next thing that shows up in my email occasionally, ripe for disruption, is <em>success notifications</em> for scheduled jobs like database backups, and membership expiration reminders. What these types of notifications need is not a success notification, but a failure notification. Hopefully error logging catches any errors that occur during those jobs, but what happens if the cron job gets disabled?</p>

<p><em>Will you notice that you didn&#39;t get that email last night when the backups should have run?</em></p>

<p>What you really need in this situation is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dead_man%27s_switch">dead man&#39;s switch</a>. These take many forms, but at their simplest you can think of them as a grenade with the pin removed. If you loosen your grip and the &quot;spoon&quot; is released from the grenade ... boom. In digital form, releasing the spoon would be your scheduled job missing a &quot;check in,&quot; and the boom would be a notification that your job hasn&#39;t run on schedule.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2016/brain_grenade.jpg" alt="Grenade">
<small>Photo credit: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/lapolab/16833901255/">lapolab</a></small></p>

<p>Enter <a href="https://deadmanssnitch.com/r/228ab4a26f">Dead Man&#39;s Snitch</a>. This app actually started out as a side project for a local Philly entrepreneur and aquiantance of mine; and I like to support local businesses, especially when they&#39;re awesome. DMS is a web service that your job calls to &quot;check in&quot; via a simple HTTP GET request. Miss a check in and they&#39;ll let you know. There are a bunch of different schedules available, and at varying price levels you get access to different integrations (i.e. Slack).</p>

<p>There are a few nuances that I&#39;m leaving out to keep this simple, so if you&#39;re interested or just have questions, go <a href="https://deadmanssnitch.com/r/228ab4a26f">check out the site</a> for more information. And hey, maybe give the service a shot: you get 1 snitch for free into perpetuity, so why not?</p>

<p><small><em>Disclosure: The links in this post, while not a paid advertisement, are referral links. If you sign up for an account then I get a free snitch for my account. Obviously I think the service is pretty great: I have a paid account for personal use as well as a paid account for my business; and I&#39;m hoping you will sign up too. But if referral links just aren&#39;t your thing, <a href="https://deadmanssnitch.com/">here&#39;s a clean one</a>.</em></small></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Welcome to OSX, 2016 Edition</title>
	  <link>//welcome-to-osx-2016-edition/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-08T08:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//welcome-to-osx-2016-edition/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Recently a friend told me that he had switched to a Mac full time and asked if I had any advice for software, or just in terms of general usage. I would have swarn that I already had a blog post on the topic that I wanted to link to him (outdated though it may be), but try as I might I couldn&#39;t find it. So here we go, I&#39;m starting from scratch!</p>

<h2>Fundamental Improvements: TotalFinder, iTerm2, and TotalSpaces</h2>

<p>I find the default experience with Finder to be grating. In my Windows days I used <a href="http://www.ghisler.com/">TotalCommander</a> almost exclusively to deal with the File System, and I had memorized tons of keyboard shortcuts to the point where I almost never needed the mouse. There exists a similar app for OSX, called <a href="http://www.cocoatech.com/pathfinder/">Path Finder</a>, <em>which I don&#39;t use.</em> I first stumbled on Path Finder before I was really able to afford spending a bunch of money on apps like that (I bought my first Mac, a base-model 12&quot; macbook, refurbished, on Black Friday). In the interim I started using a free app that made my terminal into a Visor (more on that next), and then later the same developer introduced <a href="http://totalfinder.binaryage.com/">TotalFinder</a>.</p>

<p>I can&#39;t say enough good things about TotalFinder: Almost everything that gets on my nerves about the default Finder melts away with TF. I use it as a Visor (pops up from the bottom of my screen when I hit a global keyboard shortcut), frequently use the &quot;dual mode&quot; of side-by-side finders, love the Chrome tabs, and I&#39;m <em>so</em> happy to be able to force folders to sort to the top. There are many more features, but even just those alone are worth the $9 license to me.</p>

<p>Now back to that Terminal visor. BinaryAge, developers of TotalFinder, also had a free product called <a href="http://totalterminal.binaryage.com/">TotalTerminal</a> (no longer actively developed and not compatible with OSX 10.11+) which, for me, harkened back to my days playing the original Quake. With my global keyboard shortcut <code>ctrl+`</code>, an always-available terminal window would slide down from the top of the screen to await my commands. Very handy. For reasons surrounding Zsh and Oh-my-zsh, I&#39;ve abandoned the default OSX terminal app in favor of <a href="https://www.iterm2.com/">iTerm2</a>, which is much more customizable and also supports the Visor feature.</p>

<p>I have <code>alt+&grave;</code> configured as my Finder visor shortcut, and <code>ctrl+&grave;</code> for my terminal. That&#39;s the &quot;back-tick&quot; or &quot;grave&quot; character &ndash; the one above my TAB key and what you get if you omit the Shift key when typing <code>~</code>. These two things are core to the way I work on my laptop, and being on a machine without them slows me down and trips me up significantly.</p>

<p>I also use <a href="http://totalspaces.binaryage.com/">TotalSpaces</a>, though I flip between phases where I prefer everything to have its own space and everything in one space with just <code>cmd+tab</code> to switch between them. Currently the latter. Regardless, TotalSpaces is worth $9 to get back the awesome Exposé functionality from the days before Lion. <a href="http://fusiongrokker.com/post/what-i-hate-about-osx-lion-s-mission-control">I really hate Mission Control</a>.</p>

<h2>Developer Stuff</h2>

<p>In my terminal, I prefer to use Zsh with <a href="http://ohmyz.sh/">Oh-my-zsh</a>. There are dozens of great plugins and even more themes to choose from.</p>

<p>I write my code in <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/3">Sublime Text 3</a>, and also keep my eye on <a href="https://atom.io/">Atom</a> though the plugin ecosystem is still too lacking to make it my daily driver. I have already documented <a href="http://fusiongrokker.com/post/my-sublime-keymap-common-kb-shortcuts">my sublime keymap</a> pretty thoroughly. Plugins, all available through package control:</p>

<ul>
<li>AdvancedNewFile</li>
<li>AutoFileName</li>
<li>AutoSpell</li>
<li>Babel</li>
<li>Babel snippets</li>
<li>ColdFusion (sigh)</li>
<li>Color Highlighter</li>
<li>GitGutter</li>
<li>GutterColor</li>
<li>Indent XML</li>
<li>JavaScriptNext - ES6 Syntax</li>
<li>JSCS-Formatter</li>
<li>JSHint Gutter</li>
<li>LESS</li>
<li>Material Theme</li>
<li>Number King</li>
<li>Package Control</li>
<li>React Templates</li>
<li>ReactJS Snippets</li>
<li>SideBarEnhancements</li>
<li>SublimeLinter</li>
<li>SublimeLinter-jscs</li>
</ul>

<p>I also write my blog posts in Sublime using Markdown. It&#39;s all <a href="https://github.com/atuttle/blog">hosted on GitHub</a>, actually. For managing MySQL databases (local and remote) I use <a href="http://www.sequelpro.com/">Sequel Pro</a>.</p>

<p>Pretty much everything else that I use near-daily is <a href="https://nodejs.org/">Node.js</a> and node modules. I currently use Grunt pretty heavily to do LESS, Handlebars.js, and Browserify compiling, along with a few other things (sourcemaps, <a href="http://adamtuttle.codes/modern-cache-busting-for-the-platforms-of-yeasteryear/">cache busting</a>, etc); but I see myself moving toward Gulp/Webpack in the future. Just need time to learn them. If you just need to stand up a quick basic static-file web server in a random directory, I like <a href="https://github.com/knpwrs/nws">nws</a>.</p>

<p>Do enough Node stuff and eventually you&#39;ll run into native modules that require compiling locally on your system. That, or if you do any iOS development at all (even with PhoneGap), you&#39;re going to need XCode. Better to just bite the bullet early and install it / update it as needed through the App Store.</p>

<p>On the off chance that you need an (S)FTP/S3 client, <a href="https://panic.com/transmit/">Transmit</a> is pretty good.</p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/microsoft-remote-desktop/id715768417?mt=12">Microsoft Remote Desktop</a> is actually reasonably good for managing a few windows boxes remotely. And if you need to test something in Internet Explorer, you can get free virtual machines for most flavors from <a href="https://dev.windows.com/en-us/microsoft-edge/tools/vms/mac/">modern.ie</a>. I use <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads">VirtualBox</a> for my VM&#39;s.</p>

<p>Most of the time I do my Git work in the terminal, but occasionally I&#39;ll want a GUI for block-level staging or history browsing. In those cases I like <a href="https://www.sourcetreeapp.com/">SourceTree</a>.</p>

<p>I use Keynote for presentations where I won&#39;t be doing any live code demos, or various web presentation frameworks when I am.</p>

<h2>Other Great Stuff</h2>

<p>You <em>will not find a better password manager</em> than <a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword">1Password</a>. Fast, secure, and beautiful to boot. Integrates really well with major browsers and has system keyboard shortcuts for quick access. They even have an Android Keyboard that makes accessing your passwords on the go a snap. I bought a family license and forced it on my wife and mom, too. When my kids are old enough to start having passwords for stuff, they&#39;ll be forced into it too.</p>

<p>All of the computers in my house backup to <a href="https://www.backblaze.com/">Backblaze</a>.</p>

<p>For email, I&#39;ve tried a bunch over the years. None are ever as good as straight up webmail. That said, <em>all</em> of my email is through Google Mail. If you have a work Exchange server or something, I can understand why you would want a local native client. I just don&#39;t have a recommendation for you.</p>

<p>I have access to somewhere between half a dozen and a dozen calendars, and coordinating them can be a real pain. I really like <a href="https://calendar.sunrise.am/">Sunrise Calendar</a> and was deeply saddened to hear that they were aqui-hired and will be shutting down the public facing options eventually.</p>

<p>For a basic running todo list I use <a href="https://en.todoist.com/">Todoist</a>. I tried premium but didn&#39;t feel the added features were worth it to me. For taking notes, I like <a href="http://writeapp.net/mac/">Write</a>. I sync them with DropBox so that they are also available on my iPod and iPad.</p>

<p>I use <a href="https://www.libreoffice.org/">LibreOffice</a> for office documents. Whatever you do, <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/askjack/2015/sep/03/switch-openoffice-libreoffice-or-microsoft-office">don&#39;t use OpenOffice</a>!</p>

<p>If I need to record some or all of my screen, I always use QuickTime Player (should come on your Mac). I don&#39;t do a ton of video editing yet, so iMovie is still sufficient for my needs. I see <a href="http://www.apple.com/final-cut-pro/">FinalCut</a> in my future, though. Just like Windows, the best video player is <a href="http://www.videolan.org/vlc/index.html">VLC</a> hands down.</p>

<p>Need to figure out what&#39;s eating up so much disk space? Try <a href="http://www.derlien.com/">Disk Inventory X</a>.</p>

<p>I don&#39;t have any scientific data to back this up, but subjectively I feel like my eyes are <em>way</em> less strained working on the computer late at night with <a href="https://justgetflux.com/">Flux</a>. It reddens (de-blues?) your screen more as more time passes after sunset.</p>

<p>Have you got more great app suggestions? <a href="https://twitter.com/adamtuttle">Let me know what they are!</a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Expose Node.js on an IIS Server by Reverse Proxying With ARR</title>
	  <link>//add-node-to-existing-iis-server/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-18T03:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//add-node-to-existing-iis-server/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Here&#39;s something I&#39;ve wanted to be able to do for a long time now: I have a Windows server, running IIS and a dozen or so websites on various technologies like PHP, CFML, and ASP.NET. I&#39;d like to add node.js support to that mix without disrupting any of the existing websites.</p>

<p><strong>Last night I finally figured out how!</strong> It was the result of a lot of google searches and trial-and-error, so I&#39;m no expert on the settings I&#39;ll be showing here, but it definitely works. <em>Have you got a better method? Please <a href="https://twitter.com/adamtuttle">hit me up on twitter!</a></em></p>

<p>Granted: Windows is not an ideal environment to host node apps, but you can still get a lot done with it, so you might as well know how to use what&#39;s at your disposal.</p>

<h2>Let&#39;s do it!</h2>

<p>First things first, you need to be running IIS7 or later, and you need to <a href="http://www.iis.net/downloads/microsoft/application-request-routing">install Application Request Routing (ARR)</a>.</p>

<p>Then, you need your server to accept network connections for your desired hostname. Add a website as you normally would, binding the hostname to the desired IP address:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/iis-node-website.png" alt="Configure the website as you normally would"></p>

<p>Next, we need to setup a virtual Server Farm (Microsoft&#39;s vocabulary, not mine). After you&#39;ve installed ARR, you should have a new section in the sidebar of IIS labeled <strong>Server Farms</strong>. Right click that and choose <strong>Create Server Farm</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/iis-node-create-server-farm.png" alt="Create a new server farm"></p>

<p>Give your server farm a name &ndash; anything will do &ndash; I named mine <code>localhost</code>. Make sure to check the <code>online</code> box. Click the <code>Next</code> button, and enter <code>127.0.0.1</code>  as the server address. Again, check the <code>online</code> box and enable <code>Advanced settings...</code>. Expand the newly available advanced settings, and change the http port to match the port your node web app will listen to.</p>

<p>If your node app is using express and binds to port 3000 like so: <code>app.listen(3000)</code>, then you&#39;ll enter port 3000 for the <code>httpPort</code> row.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/iis-node-farm-settings.png" alt="Server farm settings"></p>

<p>Click the <code>Finish</code> button and then <em>decline</em> the offer to add Rewrite Rules automatically (click the <code>No</code> button).</p>

<p>Select your new Farm in the sidebar, and you should be presented with a list of options like this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/iis-node-farm-tiles.png" alt="Server farm tiles"></p>

<p>Open the <code>Caching</code> options and disable disk cache. This is one of those things that I don&#39;t know is strictly necessary for my goal of running Node, but I saw it recommended in a blog post somewhere (regarding ASP.NET sites using Linq), and it&#39;s working for me, so why not?</p>

<p>Then go into <code>Routing Rules</code> and select <code>URL Rewrite...</code> from the actions panel on the right. After you do this, you should notice that the Server object in the left panel has become selected, rather than your server farm. This is expected: the change you&#39;re making will apply to the whole server.</p>

<p>You shouldn&#39;t have any rules configured yet, but if you do, edit it &ndash; otherwise create one. Use these settings:</p>

<ul>
<li>Change <code>Regular Expressions</code> to <code>Wildcards</code></li>
<li>Enter <code>*</code> for the pattern</li>
<li>Add a new condition

<ul>
<li>Condition input: <code>{HTTP_HOST}</code> (I had trouble with this at first and it <em>may</em> have been because I copy/pasted that string in. I recommend typing it manually. There should be autocomplete to help.)</li>
<li>Check: <code>Matches the pattern</code></li>
<li>Pattern: The hostname of the website you want to be bound to your node app. For this example I&#39;m using <code>www.hooli.xyz</code>.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Change Action Type to: <code>Route to server farm</code> and select the server farm you created for your node app</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/iis-node-rewrite-config.png" alt="Rewrite settings"></p>

<p>Now start up your node app and load the domain in your browser. It should all be configured and working!</p>

<p>If you want to spin up more node apps, they&#39;ll need to listen on a different port, and you&#39;ll want to add more Server Farms and routing rules to route requests to a specific farm based on the <code>{HTTP_HOST}</code> value.</p>

<h2>Where to go from here</h2>

<p>In theory it should be easy to take this a step further and run multiple node processes for the same app that listen on different ports, and use IIS as a load balancer between them. Perhaps a topic for a future blog entry.</p>

<h2>Shortfalls</h2>

<p>Coming from a background like CFML or PHP where the app server is (typically) shared by all websites I sometimes found myself wishing for a simpler connection process, but then I would remember that separation of processes is a strength, not a weakness. If one website falls over, none of the others are necessarily affected. Still, it would be nice if it was less work to add a new node-powered website.</p>

<h2>What did I get wrong?</h2>

<p>I&#39;m probably jinxing it by referencing <a href="https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cunningham%27s_Law">Cunningham&#39;s Law</a>; but here goes anyway. &quot;The best way to get the right answer on the Internet is not to ask a question, it&#39;s to post the wrong answer.&quot;</p>

<p>Are you dying to point out how horribly wrong I am? <a href="https://twitter.com/adamtuttle">Please tweet at me!</a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>My First 100 Jumps</title>
	  <link>//my-first-100-jumps/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-10T14:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//my-first-100-jumps/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Just shy of two weeks ago I completed my 100th skydive, which was a huge accomplishment for me. It took me around 18 months to collect that many (not counting the 15 year layoff between jumps #1 and #2).</p>

<p>This isn&#39;t some sort of brag: 100 is only a drop in the bucket in the average skydiving career. People that work in the sport can get thousands of jumps in a year. Most active hobbyist jumpers these days don&#39;t have much trouble getting 100+ in a year; and in fact I&#39;m hoping to come close to that for calendar year 2016, but for {reasons} I am not able to jump as often as I&#39;d like. Also, there are additional restrictions while you&#39;re a student, which I was from May (#2) to August 2014 (#25), resulting in reduced jump numbers.</p>

<p>Let&#39;s be honest: I&#39;d jump twenty times every day if I could, so there&#39;s probably no reasonable amount that will satisfy the &quot;as much as I&#39;d like&quot; criteria.</p>

<p>Anyway, here is a compilation of some of the video from my first 100 jumps.</p>

<iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/51kxI9zvauI?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Jump #100 is not included in the compilation because nobody on the jump had a camera. C&#39;est la vie.</p>

<p>For those of you wondering, in the USA you&#39;re not allowed to wear a camera until around 200 jumps. There are more rules and it gets more technical than that, but we&#39;ll just leave it at: wearing a camera is something I still have to look forward to, not something I can do yet.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Modern Cache Busting for the Platforms of Yesteryear</title>
	  <link>//modern-cache-busting-for-the-platforms-of-yeasteryear/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-25T11:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//modern-cache-busting-for-the-platforms-of-yeasteryear/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>If you work with a platform born in the last 5-10 years, chances are pretty good you&#39;ve got something like the <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/asset_pipeline.html">Rails asset pipeline</a> to take care of stuff like this for you. But if your platform of choice (or in my case this time... platform of consequence) doesn&#39;t handle it for you, you may be wondering how best to integrate cache busting into your application.</p>

<p>The application I&#39;m working on is built on ColdFusion, and it doesn&#39;t do this job for me. There are a lot of things I wish CF did that it doesn&#39;t, and when appropriate I solve these problems with a Grunt task. This application has a dozen or so different grunt tasks. Today I added cache busting, and I thought I&#39;d share the process with you. It took me a few minutes of noodling about the best way to <em>automate</em> the process to land on this solution.</p>

<p>Typically, the most basic cache busting is done by appending a query string to the request and changing that query string when you know that the file has changed:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-html" data-lang="html"><span class="nt">&lt;link</span> <span class="na">rel=</span><span class="s">&quot;stylesheet&quot;</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">&quot;style.css?bust_cache=123&quot;</span> <span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>I knew I wanted something that didn&#39;t require every developer on the team to have to know and remember to update a version number in the layout file any time they made a CSS change. Since we&#39;re already using Grunt to compile our LESS into CSS, it made sense to find a way to build it into that process, thus nothing new for the team to remember.</p>

<p>The first step was to register a new Grunt task to create my cache-busting value. I went with an MD5 hash of the current time, but there are lots of other alternative approaches you can employ. Another popular one is to MD5 hash the entire file.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="nx">grunt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">registerTask</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;cache-bust-admin&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">newHash</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">md5</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nb">Date</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">getTime</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">toString</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="nx">fs</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">writeFileSync</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;./cache-admin.md5&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">newHash</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;utf8&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
<span class="p">});</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>With this added to my Gruntfile, I added my new task to the task-set that&#39;s run automatically when LESS files change:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="p">,</span><span class="nx">watch</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="nx">less_admin</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="nx">files</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;www/admin/assets/css/*.*&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="s1">&#39;www/admin/assets/less/**&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span>
        <span class="p">,</span><span class="nx">tasks</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;css:admin&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="hll"><span class="nx">grunt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">registerTask</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;css:admin&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;less:admin&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="s1">&#39;cache-bust-admin&#39;</span><span class="p">]);</span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Now, every time the CSS updates, <code>cache-admin.md5</code> updates too. The next step is to load it into my application, and then reference it from my layout. In my <code>Application.cfc</code> file:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">onApplicationStart</span><span class="p">(){</span>
    <span class="cm">/* ... */</span>

<span class="hll">    <span class="nx">application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">cache_hash</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">fileRead</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span><span class="hll">        <span class="nx">expandPath</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;../../cache-admin.md5&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class="hll">        <span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;utf-8&quot;</span>
</span><span class="hll">    <span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class="p">}</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>And the layout:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-html" data-lang="html"><span class="nt">&lt;cfoutput&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;link</span> <span class="na">rel=</span><span class="s">&quot;stylesheet&quot;</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">&quot;style.css?cache=#application.cache_hash#&quot;</span> <span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/cfoutput&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>Every time we reinitialize our application &ndash; part of an automated deploy &ndash; it will read the contents of the <code>cache-admin.md5</code> file and store it in memory; then use that value to ensure css is always updated in the browser, while maintaining aggressive cacheing.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Three Reasons We Went Solar (and You Should Too!)</title>
	  <link>//three-reasons-we-went-solar-and-you-should-too/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-17T11:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//three-reasons-we-went-solar-and-you-should-too/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Last June, I called my buddy Mike and told him I wanted to go solar. We were about to move into our new house and I wanted him to look at the roof on Google Maps to confirm it would be worth installing solar panels. At the time he was a salesman (he&#39;s since been promoted) for <a href="https://share.solarcity.com/adamtuttle">Solar City</a>, and I know he&#39;ll always be honest with me even when he&#39;s trying to sell me something.</p>

<p>Six days ago (in terrible weather for solar energy production) we turned our system on!</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hcAEw0Ft8G8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Solar energy is really hot right now. Every time I mention our system on Facebook and Twitter I get more people asking me for details about what we paid, how much we&#39;re saving, and so on. Everybody wants in. And the good news is it&#39;s unbelievably easy, and the savings are real.</p>

<p>Here&#39;s our electric consumption compared with our solar production for yesterday. And remember, it&#39;s almost winter here in the northern hemisphere, so we&#39;re almost opposite of ideal conditions. This is only going to get better during the summer!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/solar-usage.png" alt="Our solar production vs power consumption for Nov 16th"></p>

<p>Here, then, are the very first three reasons that come to mind when asked why I wanted to go solar, and you should too:</p>

<h2>1: It&#39;s good for the planet!</h2>

<p>The sun is a renewable energy source that will be around billions of years after the last humans die (if we stay on our current trajectory, at least), and it&#39;s free. Just look up. Feel that warmth on your face? Free energy.</p>

<p>Not dumping tons of carbon and other gross polution into the atmosphere is another added bonus.</p>

<p>Really, do I have to sell the whole &quot;it&#39;s good for the environment&quot; thing that hard? I think pretty much everyone agrees that solar energy is much better than fossil fuels and easier to harness than wind or water.</p>

<h2>2: Elon Musk, evil genius</h2>

<p>Of course, Solar City makes some money from the contract they sign with you. How else would they pay for sales staff, installers, and so forth?</p>

<p>The federal government provides a nice Alternative Energy Credit to the owner of the solar system. Since we lease our system from Solar City, they own it, and they get to pocket that AEC. Then there&#39;s the profit from selling any over-produced energy back into the grid. I&#39;ll cover some of the details from that in a later section, but for now just know: They make a profit and Elon Musk turns around and reinvests that money in making the world a better place. (That&#39;s my educated guess based on his current interests: Solar City, SpaceX, Tesla, etc)</p>

<p>I love supporting a business that&#39;s out to make the world better, not just to make the shareholders rich.</p>

<h2>3: We save money &amp; it costs us <em>nothing*</em></h2>

<p>I know you&#39;re cringing at that asterisk. Give me a chance to explain!</p>

<p>No matter what, there are no up-front costs. We&#39;ve paid nothing so far, and that has covered a site inspector, the installation crew and the solar panels themselves, and a few inspections after installation. All for $0.</p>

<p>We signed a 20 year, fixed-rate contract at a per-kWh rate that is currently <em>higher</em> than what PECO charges. We&#39;re paying 15.67 cents per kWh that our solar panels produce, while PECO is only charging 13.9 per kWh that we consume from the grid. The electric utility industry, on average nationally, increases rates by 5% per year, so by year 6 we&#39;ll be saving money compared to PECO, according to those projections.</p>

<p>Our contract is the green bars, and the PECO projection is the red bars.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/solar-rates.png" alt="Solar City rates (actual) vs Peco rates (projection) over the next 20 years"></p>

<p>But what are those blue bars? That&#39;s where the asterisk comes in.</p>

<p>We chose a contract that has a higher initial per-kWh rate initially, but is fixed for 20 years. We&#39;re going to lose a little bit of money every year until that fixed rate is lower than the PECO rate. But...</p>

<p>For people that want to start saving money immediately, Solar City offers a similarly-increasing rate plan, but the amount it will increase is fixed at 2.9% and will not change for the life of your contract; <em>and</em> they start you out lower than PECO rates, so you start saving immediately. As you can see, the blue bar starts below the red bar and never goes above it.</p>

<p>How much more are we going to save over the life of the contract by signing up for the fixed rate (green bar) plan?</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/solar-savings.png" alt="Amount saved over time, two Solar City plans compared"></p>

<p>At the end of your 20 year contract, you&#39;ve saved a bunch of money... And contributed to saving the planet in a meaningful way! But what&#39;s the real dollar difference between the two plans? In order to calculate this we need a rough estimate of the number of kWh used per year, which for my family is currently about 9,200 kWh/y.</p>

<p>On the increasing rate plan (blue bar), we would save about $66 in the first year, and by the end of year 20 we would have saved a combined total of $5,658 and change (about $282/year). On the fixed rate plan (green bar) we&#39;re going to lose money for the first few years, and then once our rate is better than PECO&#39;s it&#39;s going to take a few more years worth of savings to recoup those first years losses; but then the savings take off. We&#39;ll lose $229 in our first year, and in year 5 our total combined loss will be up to $637 and change (about $127/year). But by year 20, including those losses up front, we will have saved $7,367 and change compared to the PECO projection (about $368/year).</p>

<p>Because we&#39;re willing to take a little bit of a loss for the first few years, we&#39;ll save roughly an extra $1,700 over the 20 years of the contract.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>This is probably a good time to mention that your rates <strong>will vary</strong>. These numbers are all based on what <em>my</em> electric utility is charging <em>me</em>, and the rates that Solar City <em>offered me</em>. Unless you live near me, your starting rates will probably differ, and the rates that Solar City offers you will probably differ. But the intent will be the same.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>How can they afford to do this?</h2>

<p>I don&#39;t have special access or Nate-Silver-like abilities to divine truth from seemingly unrelated numbers, but there are a few things that we know for sure.</p>

<ul>
<li>Solar City charges you nothing for your panels and other expenses (installation, etc), and recovers those costs through income streams; making it <em>really easy</em> for anyone with appropriate roof space to get involved. For the average consumer, the cost of the panels alone would be prohibitive to going solar independently.</li>
<li>Your electric utility will pay Solar City for any energy your system pushes back into the grid (after net metering)</li>
<li>The federal government (and perhaps some states?) incentivize alternative energy with Alternative Engergy Credits, which is basically a rebate they pay you for using clean energy like solar power. That goes to the owner of the solar system, which is Solar City, not you.</li>
</ul>

<h3>What&#39;s net metering?</h3>

<p>When you use electricity from the grid, your power meter spins in one direction. If you produce more energy than you consume, it will be pushed back into the grid and your meter will spin <em>backwards</em>.</p>

<p>Now imagine someone reading your meter on the 1st of the month, and it&#39;s at 5,000. When she comes back to read it on the 1st of the following month, it&#39;s at 5,300, and you&#39;re charged for 300 kWh of usage. But what the meter doesn&#39;t show is that during the beginning of the month the weather was outstanding and your meter spun backwards to 4,800; before the sky turned black and you had to start drawing energy from the grid again.</p>

<p>All that matters is that your <em>net</em> usage from the grid was 300 kWh. That&#39;s net-metering.</p>

<p>If the reading on the 1st day of the second month was 4,500, that would represent 500 kWh pushed back into the grid, and <em>they</em> would pay <em>you</em> rather than the other way around.</p>

<h2>Sounds great, where do I sign up?!</h2>

<p>After learning all of these facts, this is how I felt:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/take-my-money.gif" alt="shut up and take my money!"></p>

<p>If you feel the same way, here&#39;s some information to help you get started:</p>

<p>Solar City is licensed to operate in 31 US states and Washington, D.C. &mdash; <a href="http://www.solarcity.com/company/contractor-licenses">check here to see if your state is on the list</a>.</p>

<p>If you&#39;re in a state where they operate, <a href="https://share.solarcity.com/adamtuttle">get in touch with them!</a> Or, if you&#39;d rather start talking directly with a person (and I know you), get in touch with me and I&#39;ll put you in contact with my salesman Mike.</p>

<h3>Referral Disclosure</h3>

<p>I wrote this post because I simply can not keep up with people asking me for details on my solar setup. I believe in the company (I signed a 20 year contract with them!) and I believe they will do right by you, too. I wouldn&#39;t share this information if that weren&#39;t true. But, in the interest of disclosure, I do stand to make a little bit of money if you sign up.</p>

<p>If you use <a href="https://share.solarcity.com/adamtuttle">my referral link</a> to initiate contact with Solar City and you ultimately do get a solar system installed, <strong>your first month is free</strong> and I get $250.</p>

<p>I hope you do, for our planet&#39;s sake.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
