<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>github.com/atuttle/blog</title>
   
   <link>http://adamtuttle.codes</link>
   <description>It's one thing to write code. It's another to humanize technology so it serves a purpose in people's lives. &mdash; Luke Wroblewski</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Adam Tuttle</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>My First 100 Jumps</title>
	  <link>//my-first-100-jumps/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-10T14:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//my-first-100-jumps/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Just shy of two weeks ago I completed my 100th skydive, which was a huge accomplishment for me. It took me around 18 months to collect that many (not counting the 15 year layoff between jumps #1 and #2).</p>

<p>This isn&#39;t some sort of brag: 100 is only a drop in the bucket in the average skydiving career. People that work in the sport can get thousands of jumps in a year. Most active hobbyist jumpers these days don&#39;t have much trouble getting 100+ in a year; and in fact I&#39;m hoping to come close to that for calendar year 2016, but for {reasons} I am not able to jump as often as I&#39;d like. Also, there are additional restrictions while you&#39;re a student, which I was from May (#2) to August 2014 (#25), resulting in reduced jump numbers.</p>

<p>Let&#39;s be honest: I&#39;d jump twenty times every day if I could, so there&#39;s probably no reasonable amount that will satisfy the &quot;as much as I&#39;d like&quot; criteria.</p>

<p>Anyway, here is a compilation of some of the video from my first 100 jumps.</p>

<iframe width="1280" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/51kxI9zvauI?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Jump #100 is not included in the compilation because nobody on the jump had a camera. C&#39;est la vie.</p>

<p>For those of you wondering, in the USA you&#39;re not allowed to wear a camera until around 200 jumps. There are more rules and it gets more technical than that, but we&#39;ll just leave it at: wearing a camera is something I still have to look forward to, not something I can do yet.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Modern Cache Busting for the Platforms of Yesteryear</title>
	  <link>//modern-cache-busting-for-the-platforms-of-yeasteryear/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-25T11:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//modern-cache-busting-for-the-platforms-of-yeasteryear/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>If you work with a platform born in the last 5-10 years, chances are pretty good you&#39;ve got something like the <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/asset_pipeline.html">Rails asset pipeline</a> to take care of stuff like this for you. But if your platform of choice (or in my case this time... platform of consequence) doesn&#39;t handle it for you, you may be wondering how best to integrate cache busting into your application.</p>

<p>The application I&#39;m working on is built on ColdFusion, and it doesn&#39;t do this job for me. There are a lot of things I wish CF did that it doesn&#39;t, and when appropriate I solve these problems with a Grunt task. This application has a dozen or so different grunt tasks. Today I added cache busting, and I thought I&#39;d share the process with you. It took me a few minutes of noodling about the best way to <em>automate</em> the process to land on this solution.</p>

<p>Typically, the most basic cache busting is done by appending a query string to the request and changing that query string when you know that the file has changed:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-html" data-lang="html"><span class="nt">&lt;link</span> <span class="na">rel=</span><span class="s">&quot;stylesheet&quot;</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">&quot;style.css?bust_cache=123&quot;</span> <span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>I knew I wanted something that didn&#39;t require every developer on the team to have to know and remember to update a version number in the layout file any time they made a CSS change. Since we&#39;re already using Grunt to compile our LESS into CSS, it made sense to find a way to build it into that process, thus nothing new for the team to remember.</p>

<p>The first step was to register a new Grunt task to create my cache-busting value. I went with an MD5 hash of the current time, but there are lots of other alternative approaches you can employ. Another popular one is to MD5 hash the entire file.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="nx">grunt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">registerTask</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;cache-bust-admin&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">newHash</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">md5</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="nb">Date</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">getTime</span><span class="p">().</span><span class="nx">toString</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="nx">fs</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">writeFileSync</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;./cache-admin.md5&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">newHash</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;utf8&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
<span class="p">});</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>With this added to my Gruntfile, I added my new task to the task-set that&#39;s run automatically when LESS files change:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="p">,</span><span class="nx">watch</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="nx">less_admin</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="nx">files</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;www/admin/assets/css/*.*&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="s1">&#39;www/admin/assets/less/**&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span>
        <span class="p">,</span><span class="nx">tasks</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;css:admin&#39;</span><span class="p">]</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="hll"><span class="nx">grunt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">registerTask</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;css:admin&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;less:admin&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="s1">&#39;cache-bust-admin&#39;</span><span class="p">]);</span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Now, every time the CSS updates, <code>cache-admin.md5</code> updates too. The next step is to load it into my application, and then reference it from my layout. In my <code>Application.cfc</code> file:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">onApplicationStart</span><span class="p">(){</span>
    <span class="cm">/* ... */</span>

<span class="hll">    <span class="nx">application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">cache_hash</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">fileRead</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span><span class="hll">        <span class="nx">expandPath</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;../../cache-admin.md5&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class="hll">        <span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;utf-8&quot;</span>
</span><span class="hll">    <span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class="p">}</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>And the layout:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-html" data-lang="html"><span class="nt">&lt;cfoutput&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;link</span> <span class="na">rel=</span><span class="s">&quot;stylesheet&quot;</span> <span class="na">href=</span><span class="s">&quot;style.css?cache=#application.cache_hash#&quot;</span> <span class="nt">/&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/cfoutput&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>Every time we reinitialize our application &ndash; part of an automated deploy &ndash; it will read the contents of the <code>cache-admin.md5</code> file and store it in memory; then use that value to ensure css is always updated in the browser, while maintaining aggressive cacheing.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Three Reasons We Went Solar (and You Should Too!)</title>
	  <link>//three-reasons-we-went-solar-and-you-should-too/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-17T11:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//three-reasons-we-went-solar-and-you-should-too/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Last June, I called my buddy Mike and told him I wanted to go solar. We were about to move into our new house and I wanted him to look at the roof on Google Maps to confirm it would be worth installing solar panels. At the time he was a salesman (he&#39;s since been promoted) for <a href="https://share.solarcity.com/adamtuttle">Solar City</a>, and I know he&#39;ll always be honest with me even when he&#39;s trying to sell me something.</p>

<p>Six days ago (in terrible weather for solar energy production) we turned our system on!</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hcAEw0Ft8G8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Solar energy is really hot right now. Every time I mention our system on Facebook and Twitter I get more people asking me for details about what we paid, how much we&#39;re saving, and so on. Everybody wants in. And the good news is it&#39;s unbelievably easy, and the savings are real.</p>

<p>Here&#39;s our electric consumption compared with our solar production for yesterday. And remember, it&#39;s almost winter here in the northern hemisphere, so we&#39;re almost opposite of ideal conditions. This is only going to get better during the summer!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/solar-usage.png" alt="Our solar production vs power consumption for Nov 16th"></p>

<p>Here, then, are the very first three reasons that come to mind when asked why I wanted to go solar, and you should too:</p>

<h2>1: It&#39;s good for the planet!</h2>

<p>The sun is a renewable energy source that will be around billions of years after the last humans die (if we stay on our current trajectory, at least), and it&#39;s free. Just look up. Feel that warmth on your face? Free energy.</p>

<p>Not dumping tons of carbon and other gross polution into the atmosphere is another added bonus.</p>

<p>Really, do I have to sell the whole &quot;it&#39;s good for the environment&quot; thing that hard? I think pretty much everyone agrees that solar energy is much better than fossil fuels and easier to harness than wind or water.</p>

<h2>2: Elon Musk, evil genius</h2>

<p>Of course, Solar City makes some money from the contract they sign with you. How else would they pay for sales staff, installers, and so forth?</p>

<p>The federal government provides a nice Alternative Energy Credit to the owner of the solar system. Since we lease our system from Solar City, they own it, and they get to pocket that AEC. Then there&#39;s the profit from selling any over-produced energy back into the grid. I&#39;ll cover some of the details from that in a later section, but for now just know: They make a profit and Elon Musk turns around and reinvests that money in making the world a better place. (That&#39;s my educated guess based on his current interests: Solar City, SpaceX, Tesla, etc)</p>

<p>I love supporting a business that&#39;s out to make the world better, not just to make the shareholders rich.</p>

<h2>3: We save money &amp; it costs us <em>nothing*</em></h2>

<p>I know you&#39;re cringing at that asterisk. Give me a chance to explain!</p>

<p>No matter what, there are no up-front costs. We&#39;ve paid nothing so far, and that has covered a site inspector, the installation crew and the solar panels themselves, and a few inspections after installation. All for $0.</p>

<p>We signed a 20 year, fixed-rate contract at a per-kWh rate that is currently <em>higher</em> than what PECO charges. We&#39;re paying 15.67 cents per kWh that our solar panels produce, while PECO is only charging 13.9 per kWh that we consume from the grid. The electric utility industry, on average nationally, increases rates by 5% per year, so by year 6 we&#39;ll be saving money compared to PECO, according to those projections.</p>

<p>Our contract is the green bars, and the PECO projection is the red bars.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/solar-rates.png" alt="Solar City rates (actual) vs Peco rates (projection) over the next 20 years"></p>

<p>But what are those blue bars? That&#39;s where the asterisk comes in.</p>

<p>We chose a contract that has a higher initial per-kWh rate initially, but is fixed for 20 years. We&#39;re going to lose a little bit of money every year until that fixed rate is lower than the PECO rate. But...</p>

<p>For people that want to start saving money immediately, Solar City offers a similarly-increasing rate plan, but the amount it will increase is fixed at 2.9% and will not change for the life of your contract; <em>and</em> they start you out lower than PECO rates, so you start saving immediately. As you can see, the blue bar starts below the red bar and never goes above it.</p>

<p>How much more are we going to save over the life of the contract by signing up for the fixed rate (green bar) plan?</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/solar-savings.png" alt="Amount saved over time, two Solar City plans compared"></p>

<p>At the end of your 20 year contract, you&#39;ve saved a bunch of money... And contributed to saving the planet in a meaningful way! But what&#39;s the real dollar difference between the two plans? In order to calculate this we need a rough estimate of the number of kWh used per year, which for my family is currently about 9,200 kWh/y.</p>

<p>On the increasing rate plan (blue bar), we would save about $66 in the first year, and by the end of year 20 we would have saved a combined total of $5,658 and change (about $282/year). On the fixed rate plan (green bar) we&#39;re going to lose money for the first few years, and then once our rate is better than PECO&#39;s it&#39;s going to take a few more years worth of savings to recoup those first years losses; but then the savings take off. We&#39;ll lose $229 in our first year, and in year 5 our total combined loss will be up to $637 and change (about $127/year). But by year 20, including those losses up front, we will have saved $7,367 and change compared to the PECO projection (about $368/year).</p>

<p>Because we&#39;re willing to take a little bit of a loss for the first few years, we&#39;ll save roughly an extra $1,700 over the 20 years of the contract.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>This is probably a good time to mention that your rates <strong>will vary</strong>. These numbers are all based on what <em>my</em> electric utility is charging <em>me</em>, and the rates that Solar City <em>offered me</em>. Unless you live near me, your starting rates will probably differ, and the rates that Solar City offers you will probably differ. But the intent will be the same.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>How can they afford to do this?</h2>

<p>I don&#39;t have special access or Nate-Silver-like abilities to divine truth from seemingly unrelated numbers, but there are a few things that we know for sure.</p>

<ul>
<li>Solar City charges you nothing for your panels and other expenses (installation, etc), and recovers those costs through income streams; making it <em>really easy</em> for anyone with appropriate roof space to get involved. For the average consumer, the cost of the panels alone would be prohibitive to going solar independently.</li>
<li>Your electric utility will pay Solar City for any energy your system pushes back into the grid (after net metering)</li>
<li>The federal government (and perhaps some states?) incentivize alternative energy with Alternative Engergy Credits, which is basically a rebate they pay you for using clean energy like solar power. That goes to the owner of the solar system, which is Solar City, not you.</li>
</ul>

<h3>What&#39;s net metering?</h3>

<p>When you use electricity from the grid, your power meter spins in one direction. If you produce more energy than you consume, it will be pushed back into the grid and your meter will spin <em>backwards</em>.</p>

<p>Now imagine someone reading your meter on the 1st of the month, and it&#39;s at 5,000. When she comes back to read it on the 1st of the following month, it&#39;s at 5,300, and you&#39;re charged for 300 kWh of usage. But what the meter doesn&#39;t show is that during the beginning of the month the weather was outstanding and your meter spun backwards to 4,800; before the sky turned black and you had to start drawing energy from the grid again.</p>

<p>All that matters is that your <em>net</em> usage from the grid was 300 kWh. That&#39;s net-metering.</p>

<p>If the reading on the 1st day of the second month was 4,500, that would represent 500 kWh pushed back into the grid, and <em>they</em> would pay <em>you</em> rather than the other way around.</p>

<h2>Sounds great, where do I sign up?!</h2>

<p>After learning all of these facts, this is how I felt:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/take-my-money.gif" alt="shut up and take my money!"></p>

<p>If you feel the same way, here&#39;s some information to help you get started:</p>

<p>Solar City is licensed to operate in 31 US states and Washington, D.C. &mdash; <a href="http://www.solarcity.com/company/contractor-licenses">check here to see if your state is on the list</a>.</p>

<p>If you&#39;re in a state where they operate, <a href="https://share.solarcity.com/adamtuttle">get in touch with them!</a> Or, if you&#39;d rather start talking directly with a person (and I know you), get in touch with me and I&#39;ll put you in contact with my salesman Mike.</p>

<h3>Referral Disclosure</h3>

<p>I wrote this post because I simply can not keep up with people asking me for details on my solar setup. I believe in the company (I signed a 20 year contract with them!) and I believe they will do right by you, too. I wouldn&#39;t share this information if that weren&#39;t true. But, in the interest of disclosure, I do stand to make a little bit of money if you sign up.</p>

<p>If you use <a href="https://share.solarcity.com/adamtuttle">my referral link</a> to initiate contact with Solar City and you ultimately do get a solar system installed, <strong>your first month is free</strong> and I get $250.</p>

<p>I hope you do, for our planet&#39;s sake.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Extra Life 2015 Recap</title>
	  <link>//extra-life-2015-recap/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-12T03:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//extra-life-2015-recap/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><em>Thank you.</em> Wow.</p>

<p>I really needed to open with that, because I did not deserve the support I received over the course of the 24 hours leading up to my Extra Life marathon&mdash;or during it, for that matter&mdash;and I am so grateful.</p>

<p>The truth is that I procrastinated too much this year. Not just for Extra Life, but that too. A long time ago I signed up and made my own donation, and when the occasional opportunity arose I asked for donations there in lieu of people offering me beer money for something. But that was it until the day before I was scheduled to sit down for 24 hours of fun and, mostly, isolation. (A rare treat as a parent!)</p>

<p>On Friday evening, 24 hours before go-time, I had amassed $130 in donations. For sure, nothing to be ashamed of; but paling in comparison to my 2013 total of $1,088. The difference, obviously, was that I hadn&#39;t made much of an effort at all.</p>

<p>So I wrote a blog post here <a href="http://adamtuttle.codes/extra-life-2015/">soliciting donations</a>, and started hyping it on Twitter and Facebook. I figured if I was going to abandon my family for 24 hours to play games with the excuse that it was for charity, I at least had to <em>try</em> to raise more money. I also planned to stay in a Google Hangout for as much of the marathon as I could. Some people have fancy twitch tv streaming setups (I do not), so pointing my laptop at the tv and my tablet at myself is about the best I can do at the moment.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I will 🐦tweet the Hangout link once it&#39;s open, of course! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ExtraLife?src=hash">#ExtraLife</a>&#10;&#10;💰Donations here! <a href="https://t.co/ilhhdfMQzw">https://t.co/ilhhdfMQzw</a>&#10;&#10;Do it for the kids! 👶👼</p>&mdash; Adam Tuttle (@AdamTuttle) <a href="https://twitter.com/AdamTuttle/status/663117733807034368">November 7, 2015</a></blockquote>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Maybe I should do this like the NPR pledge drive.&#10;&#10;I tweet every 5m until I hit my <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ExtraLife?src=hash">#ExtraLife</a> goal or they take me off the air.&#10;&#10;Kidding 😜</p>&mdash; Adam Tuttle (@AdamTuttle) <a href="https://twitter.com/AdamTuttle/status/663122737343238145">November 7, 2015</a></blockquote>

<p>And to my amazement, it happened. I didn&#39;t deserve it. I hadn&#39;t earned it. But it happened anyway.</p>

<p>My campaign added another $350 from 8 donors over that 48 hour period, bringing my total to $480 &ndash; an amount that allowed me to continue making eye contact with Megan when I ask her to tend to every need of our children (and cook for me!) for 24 hours so that I can go play games.</p>

<p>It bears repeating: <em>thank you.</em></p>

<p><img src="http://adamtuttle.codes/assets/images/posts/2015/the-cake-is-a-lie.png" alt="Me after beating Portal (an Extra Life tradition of mine) around 2am"></p>

<p>And play games I did.</p>

<h2>Learn from my mistake</h2>

<p>This year I wanted to try something different. Usually I would start around 7:00 or 8:00 in the morning, finishing at the same time the following day, and then proceed to spend half (or more) of the day after trying to repay some of my sleep debt. Instead I had the bright idea that I could start at 8pm, finish at 8pm, and head to bed right about the same time as my kids; saving Megan an extra half-day of picking up my slack.</p>

<p>And at least in that regard, it was successful. What I did not plan for was my inability to nap, and thus turning my 24 hour gaming marathon into 24 hours of gaming following 14 hours of being awake for a normal Friday. I was <em>Tired</em> with a capital <em>T</em>. Some time between 1:00am and 2:00am I noticed that I was doing the &quot;long blink&quot; thing, and that even leaning forward on my knees wasn&#39;t going to keep me awake. So I stood, playing Portal, with headphones, alone, from about 2:00am to about 4:00am. At one point I started to feel like I was getting a second wind, so I sat down, but I quickly realized I was wrong and went back to standing.</p>

<h2>What I played</h2>

<p>I started the evening playing <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&field-keywords=star%20wars%20force%20unleashed%20ii&linkCode=ur2&rh=n%3A468642%2Ck%3Astar%20wars%20force%20unleashed%20ii&tag=tuttl-20&url=search-alias%3Dvideogames&linkId=FWUI56KFJBDQBRKV">Star Wars: The Force Unleashed II</a>, a game that I picked up used for a few bucks at GameStop on the recommendation of a clerk because I like Star Wars and enjoyed Dragon Age and Borderlands, but that I had yet to play. It was surprisingly fun. The cut scenes were not trying to be overly-artistic, not too long, and not too short. The game progresses from one conflict to the next very fluidly, and the mechanics are fun and, so far, not too repetitive. (I&#39;ve not finished it yet.) The boss fights are hard, and occasionally fun stuff happens like you fight while <strong>falling out of the sky</strong> (can&#39;t imagine why that would interest me...). The only reason I put it down to play something else was that I was getting too worked up! My hands were cramping and my heart was racing.</p>

<p>To relieve some of the stress from Star Wars, I initiated my Extra Life ritual of playing through the original <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&field-keywords=orange%20box&linkCode=ur2&rh=n%3A468642%2Ck%3Aorange%20box&sprefix=orange%20box%2Cvideogames%2C139&tag=tuttl-20&url=search-alias%3Dvideogames&linkId=YQUNEQHFNZRORCRU">Portal</a>. I&#39;m no <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?q=portal+speedrun">Portal speed-runner</a>, but this turned out to be the longest game of Portal in history, probably. Between the long-blinks I mentioned above, and my sleep-deprived brain simply not being able to process some of the puzzles (despite having beaten them all many times), I think it took me at least 5 hours. But beat it I did!</p>

<p>Then, because I was in the mood, I started playing <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&field-keywords=portal%202&linkCode=ur2&rh=n%3A468642%2Ck%3Aportal%202&sprefix=portal%202%2Cvideogames%2C128&tag=tuttl-20&url=search-alias%3Dvideogames&linkId=MEY2DSX5JJ63EBGA">Portal 2&#39;s</a> single player campaign. The storytelling in the second game is off the charts, and the new mechanics are just unbelievably fun. <em>Juuuust</em> as I was getting into the first puzzles of the new mechanics, around 11:00am, my brother and his girlfriend arrived. They had never been to my new house before (We moved over the summer), so I gave them a quick tour of the house and then we switched over to the two-player version of Portal 2. After a brief lunch break, we decided to play some board games with Megan and the kids.</p>

<p>We played a few hands of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&field-keywords=exploding%20kittens&linkCode=ur2&rh=n%3A165793011%2Ck%3Aexploding%20kittens&sprefix=exploding%20kittens%2Cvideogames%2C127&tag=tuttl-20&url=search-alias%3Dtoys-and-games&linkId=CERZLY2MKZXETOXE">Exploding Kittens</a> because it&#39;s silly and fun, and then a few games of <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002SQBB3O/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B002SQBB3O&linkCode=as2&tag=tuttl-20&linkId=AUT2ZMYKS5ZFQ25Y">Tsuro</a>, because it&#39;s easy enough for even my 4 year old to play on his own while still being fun and interesting for adults. Once the kids were losing interest in board games, we switched over to some 4-way <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&field-keywords=mario%20kart%20wii&linkCode=ur2&sprefix=mario%20kart%20wii%2Ctoys-and-games%2C127&tag=tuttl-20&url=search-alias%3Dvideogames&linkId=7EBAYYB5SK7O6VNE">Mario Kart Wii</a> &ndash; always a favorite.</p>

<p><img src="http://adamtuttle.codes/assets/images/posts/2015/tsuro.jpg" alt="Tsuro is a family favorite!"></p>

<p>From there we went back to play more Portal 2 until dinner, which was breakfast: Waffles, eggs, and bacon. Yum! My brother left after dinner, and I finished out the marathon playing more of the single player campaign for Portal 2.</p>

<h2>Why I play</h2>

<p>I was recently reminded of a great scene from the awesome TV show &quot;Louis&quot;:</p>

<p><img src="http://adamtuttle.codes/assets/images/posts/2015/parenting.jpg" alt="Checking your neighbor&#39;s bowl"></p>

<p>I have lived a very fortunate life, thanks to the efforts of my parents. We started out somewhere around &quot;poor&quot; and through some combination of hard work and luck manged to move a few rungs up that ladder. I&#39;m reminded of this fact every time an Amazon Prime box containing some goody shows up on my front porch. Every time I buy skydiving equipment. Every time I click my garage door opener. Every time we buy fresh produce at the grocery store.</p>

<p>I don&#39;t feel overly guilty for enjoying the fruits of my labor, but I am reminded of my sense of duty to help those less fortunate than me.</p>

<p>When I think about whose life I most want to improve if I only have a limited amount of help to give, it&#39;s kids. Without a doubt, 100%. That&#39;s why I campaign for <a href="http://extra-life.org/">Extra Life</a>, and why I give to <a href="http://childsplaycharity.org/">Child&#39;s Play</a> every year. I don&#39;t always have much to give, but I can&#39;t think of anyone more deserving of my help than children in need. After all, what did they do to deserve their current situation? They were unlucky to be born to parents without health insurance, or to have a heart condition, or cancer. And with a little helping hand, they have their whole life ahead of them.</p>

<p>I don&#39;t have some close personal tie to this cause or these particular charities beyond what I&#39;ve already said. Neither myself nor any of my family have&mdash;to the best of my knowledge&mdash;directly benefited from any of these programs. I just believe that they are worthy causes.</p>

<h2>It&#39;s not too late to give!</h2>

<p>While my 24 hour gaming marathon is over, the time to donate is not! If you wanted to make a donation but never got around to it, you&#39;ll be happy to know that donations are probably still accepted... Unless you&#39;re reading this from the future.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.extra-life.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=widgets.300x250thermo&participantID=148892" width="302" height="252" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="http://www.extra-life.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=donorDrive.participant&participantID=148892">Make a Donation!</a></iframe>

<p>If that &quot;Make a donation!&quot; button above still works, then you can still help make a difference in the life of a sick or injured child. And if it&#39;s not, there&#39;s a good chance that another year of Extra Life is going on now, or will be starting soon. <a href="https://twitter.com/adamtuttle">Reach out to me</a> and I&#39;ll be happy to direct you to the best place to make your donation.</p>

<h2>Next year...</h2>

<p>Next year I <em>will not fail to plan.</em></p>

<p><img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=tuttl-20&l=ur2&o=1" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /><script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Soliciting Extra-Life Donations for Childrens Hospital of Philadelphia!</title>
	  <link>//extra-life-2015/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-04T03:30:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//extra-life-2015/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I know this is terribly last minute, but I&#39;ve been swamped with deadlines and such and haven&#39;t had any time to actively hype my Extra Life campaign this year. <em>And it&#39;s happening this weekend!</em></p>

<p>Starting at 8pm on Saturday, November 7th (US-Eastern) I&#39;ll begin a 24 hour marathon of games of all types. Video games, Board games, card games, dice games. Maybe even some other tabletop gaming if I can arrange some friends to get together in time. And I won&#39;t stop playing, except to eat or go to the bathroom, for 24 hours. No time-outs. No tag-ins.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.extra-life.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=widgets.300x250thermo&participantID=148892" width="302" height="252" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" style="margin: 0 auto 3rem"><a href="http://www.extra-life.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=donorDrive.participant&participantID=148892">Make a Donation!</a></iframe>

<p>For the uninitiated, <a href="http://www.extra-life.org/">Extra Life</a> is a charity that collects money for Children&#39;s Miracle Network Hospitals, whose mission is to provide care for children, regardless of their family&#39;s ability to pay for it.</p>

<p>Kids with cancer, or heart issues, or that were in car accidents. The list goes on and on and on.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/dylan-xbox.jpg" alt="My son Dylan playing xbox with me"></p>

<p>They deserve our support and our help! And they&#39;re in my back yard. I play for the Children&#39;s Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP), but there are CMN Hospitals all over the world. There&#39;s probably one near you too.</p>

<h2>What I&#39;m doing for your money</h2>

<p>How does it work? Well, I usually compare it to the ACS Relay For Life, except instead of walking in circles for 24 hours we&#39;re playing games &mdash; of all varieties. The header image is of my brothers and I (and my son) playing some Rock Band during my 2013 marathon. Video games are a big part of it for most people, but I usually try to get my whole family involved by playing board and card games too.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/posts/2015/robot-turtles.jpg" alt="Robot Turtles, playing with my kids!"></p>

<p>Just like Relay for Life, it all hinges on soliciting donations from friends. <em><strong>Friends like you</strong>.</em> Would you be so kind as to donate a few dollars to help sick kids? I&#39;m attempting to raise $1,024 this year, and I could really use your help. I greatly appreciate every donation, no matter how small; but more importantly, it goes directly to helping sick kids get the medical care that they need.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.extra-life.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=widgets.300x250thermo&participantID=148892" width="302" height="252" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" style="margin: 0 auto 3rem"><a href="http://www.extra-life.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=donorDrive.participant&participantID=148892">Make a Donation!</a></iframe>

<p>What do you say? Let&#39;s help some kids!</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZS7WRl7N1Ig" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2_sLlWO_v24" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>On Old Dogs and New Tricks</title>
	  <link>//on-old-dogs-and-new-tricks/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-10-31T19:59:59-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//on-old-dogs-and-new-tricks/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Consider the following code. This isn&#39;t an exercise in figuring out what something does, or how to do it, so I&#39;ll just tell you: it updates a list of items (e.g. user input) so that all items in the list are quoted with single-quotes. If it finds them, it strips out double quotes, too (only if both open and close quotes exist).</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="nx">x</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;foo,&#39;bar&#39;,&quot;&quot;baz&quot;&quot;,qux&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>

<span class="nx">x</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">x</span>
  <span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">listToArray</span><span class="p">()</span>
<span class="hll">  <span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">map</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">){</span>
</span>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">left</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s2">&quot;&#39;&quot;</span> <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">right</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s2">&quot;&#39;&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">left</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;&quot;&#39;</span> <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">right</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;&quot;&#39;</span><span class="p">){</span>
      <span class="nx">item</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">left</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">len</span><span class="p">()</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">1</span> <span class="p">);</span> <span class="c1">//chop trailing &quot;</span>
      <span class="nx">item</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">right</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="nx">item</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">len</span><span class="p">()</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">1</span> <span class="p">);</span> <span class="c1">//chop leading &quot;</span>
      <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s2">&quot;&#39;#item#&#39;&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="s2">&quot;&#39;#item#&#39;&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
  <span class="p">})</span>
  <span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">toList</span><span class="p">();</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>Would it surprise you to find out that this code is CMFL?</p>

<p>A few short years ago (a lifetime, on the internet), I would have been shocked to see this and learn that it is, indeed, ColdFusion code. It&#39;s very <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ECMAScript">ECMAScripty</a>, it&#39;s functional, and it uses some of the language trimmings modern modern languages love: map and reduce. <code>array.toList()</code> is really just a reducer, if you think about it.</p>

<p>I&#39;m not heralding ColdFusion, here. I&#39;ve been working with the platform for more than a decade now and I&#39;m pretty sick of it, to be honest. As a former ColdFusion Product Manager once told me, &quot;You don&#39;t really know a programming language unless you can name 10 things you hate about it.&quot; By that measure, I&#39;d estimate that I know CFML really, <em>really</em>, <em><strong>really</strong></em> well.</p>

<p>Whatever your opinion of ColdFusion, it is undeniably changing. The next version is on the horizon. They&#39;re in private beta (in which I declined to participate); and I would wager public beta is closer than most people would think.</p>

<p><em>Everything old is new again.</em></p>

<p>Me, too.</p>

<p>I&#39;ll be 35 in April. While technically not even half way through my career (assuming I retire at 65), 35 feels kind of &quot;old&quot; in tech. I&#39;ve gone from being one of the hungry young guys that&#39;s eager to replace the stagnant developers that came before me, to one of those old kodgers that&#39;s unsettled (even if just a little bit) by new JS frameworks coming out every week.</p>

<p>For the last few years my developer career has started to stagnate. I decided not to speak at any conferences in 2015; in part to give myself a break from the crazy amount of work that I put into a presentation that I give only once or twice, but also in part to find out if I would miss it. (I do.) I haven&#39;t learned anything new &mdash; nothing big, at least. I haven&#39;t grown.</p>

<p>I learned the fundamentals of Node.js at the end of 2014, and have been using them to my great advantage since, but that was the last time I truly learned something new. I&#39;ve been heads-down working on <a href="http://www.alumniq.com">AlumnIQ</a>, doing the occasional freelance gig, and somehow this has filled my time. As an ambitious person, it seems weird to me to have been able to go an entire year without any major changes (never mind the fact that I bought a new house and moved in the middle of the summer, and I&#39;m a Cub Scout leader now). In some ways I was sating my need for growth by solving hard problems with boring tech.</p>

<p>It makes for (very) brief periods of excitement&mdash;problem solved! hooray! 🎉🍻&mdash;interspersed with lots of headaches and hair pulling. By contrast, when learning a new piece of technology, every time you master another bit of it you&#39;re rewarded with endorphins for having learned something new and exciting.</p>

<p>The first step is admitting you have a problem.</p>

<p>In the last two weeks, I&#39;ve started learning <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/">React</a> and really making an effort to learn <a href="https://babeljs.io/docs/learn-es2015/">ES2015</a> (I&#39;ve only dabbled until now). I haven&#39;t combined the two yet. I don&#39;t yet understand ES2015 well enough to be able to look at it and understand how it works instantly, like I can with ES5. I&#39;m also very interested in the static-website-generator craze. In fact I&#39;m writing this blog post as my first new entry to a <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> blog that I intend to host via <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>.</p>

<p>2016 will be a high-growth year for me. That&#39;s my goal. I guess I&#39;m a little early for the New Years Resolution party, but planning ahead is a good way to set myself up for success, right?</p>

<p>Now if you&#39;ll excuse me, I have some React components to write.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
