<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>github.com/atuttle/blog</title>
   
   <link>http://adamtuttle.codes</link>
   <description>It's one thing to write code. It's another to humanize technology so it serves a purpose in people's lives. &mdash; Luke Wroblewski</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Adam Tuttle</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Errors are Best When Emailed... Said Nobody Ever</title>
	  <link>//errors-are-best-when-emailed-said-nobody-ever/</link>
	  <author>Adam Tuttle</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//errors-are-best-when-emailed-said-nobody-ever/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="6142a1bd3e2b408786cf9c508c953d5c" data-ratio="1.33333333333333" src="https://speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script>

<p>Exceptions happen. Bugless code is a myth.</p>

<p>I hope I don&#39;t have to convince many people that sending every exception via email is not the greatest idea since sliced bread. &quot;Sure, it sucks... But what else can I do?&quot; would be a natural response. I&#39;ve been there. How else can you keep track of exactly what&#39;s going wrong in your application? How else will you be alerted when something goes wrong?</p>

<p>For many of you, email probably plays the role of courier between your application and your bug database (JIRA, Bugzilla, etc). But that&#39;s not what email was intended for, and to be honest, it&#39;s a poor tool for the job, so it does a crappy job.</p>

<p>The truth is that there are better options, but nobody can blame you for not knowing about them... Until now. I&#39;m going to show you the two most popular options available for CF, how to use them to get useful analytical data back about your application&#39;s health, or lack thereof, and how you can extend the concept beyond just your CFML. And the real surprise is that it&#39;s easy.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
